

# Juan Diego Giraldo Soto

**Data Analyst and Full Stack Web Developer** 

Medellín, Colombia juangiraldo222@gmail.com - (+57) 312 720 42 89

## Professional Attributes

I am a Data Analyst and Full Stack Web Developer with over 5 years of experience. I feel very comfortable working with Laravel. I do like analytics, working with R.

Technology is my passion. For me, coding is like having super powers.

Me in two words: passionate and persistent.

#### **Skills**

PHP

Laravel

Codelgniter

Jquery

SQL Server

R Studio

PostgreSQL

HTML<sub>5</sub>

CSS<sub>3</sub>

Twitter Bootstrap

Responsive Design



\*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\* \*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\* \*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\*\* \*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*

\*\*\*\*\*\*

## **Experience**

#### **FREELANCER**

2014 - Present

## **Back End Web Developer**

I worked in several project using back-end technologies:

Laravel

Composer

Homestead

MVC

MySQL

**SQL Server** 

Responsive Design

#### **Current Projects:**

Back-End developments for Magdalena Medio <a href="http://www.magdalenamedio.net/">http://www.magdalenamedio.net/</a>:

- o <a href="https://www.casatoro.com/intranet">https://www.casatoro.com/intranet</a>
- o <a href="http://aplicativoartbo.com/galerias/">http://aplicativoartbo.com/galerias/</a>
- o <a href="http://aplicativoartbo.com/macrositio/">http://aplicativoartbo.com/macrositio/</a>

The projects for Magdalena Medio are aimed to the car sales industry and Cámara de Comercio de Bogotá and it's ARTBO artists fair.

## HAPPYCHILD INC,

2016 - 2017

### **Full Stack Developer**

HappyChild is a cloud-based Child care software that allows operators to record daily activities, manage staff and communicate efficiently with parents.

I made the initial development of the platform using Laravel.

#### GAMMA GROUP - UNIVERSITY OF ANTIOQUIA

2015 - 2016

#### Chief Information Officer - CIO

Technical assistance for milk producers in the Department of Antioquia.

Data analysis and information processing. I was leading a team of 15 professionals which handled, organized and analyzed all the information from this project.

Data bases depuration

**Exploratory analysis** 

Data mining

Modellation (Linear and Logistic Models, GAMS and GAMM's)

Product testing and software adaptation

**SQL Server** 

R Project

### BLASINA & ASOCIADOS – MONTEVIDEO, URU

2013 - 2014

#### Internship

Analysis of commodities international markets for staple crops. Statistics and data analysis for market trends. Development of a strategic plan for internationalize the Colombian livestock industry.

#### Education

## UNIVERSITY OF ANTIOQUIA - Medellin, COL

2013-2015

## **Young Researcher Scholarship**

Innovative and Researcher Young Scholarship, Colciencias 2013-2014

Genetics, Selection and Animal modelation Group - GaMMA

Data Analysis and Inferential Statistics.

R Studio

Generalized Additive Models (GAM's)

Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMM's)

## UNIVERSITY OF ANTIOQUIA - Medellin, COL

2006-2013

## **Bachelor Degree in Production Systems Engineering**

#### References

## Mario Fernando Cerón Muñoz (PhD)

GaMMA Group Director University of Antioquia

Tel: 311 3184036

Email: cerongamma@gmail.com

#### **LUIS FERNANDO MONTOYA GOMEZ**

Full Stack Web Developer Sr Developer at Toptal

Tel: 311 372 77 51

Email: <u>luismec90@gmail.com</u>

#### **JOSE DANIEL RAMIREZ SOTO**

Msc Data Science University of Columbia

Data Scientist at Capital One

Email: josedaniel8505@gmail.com